Blessy Yohannan

Software Engineer

- Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Blessy-Yohannan/943196a30ffb6838

I am actively seeking for job as a software developer to leverage my prior software industry experience and classroom experience into the real world. I have 7 years of experience in full software development lifecycle - from

concept through delivery of applications. During my Masters, I used C++, JAVA, JSP, Perl, HTML, MYSQL and PHP for various projects.

My professional experience includes designing, developing and testing of Mainframe applications in Insurance, Banking and Retail domains using TSO/ISPF, SPUFI, SMF, DB2, RACF, VSAM, CICS, PLI, IMS, TELON, SQL, COBOL, MF COBOL, CA7, REXX, Assembler, C++, JAVA, XML, SOA, HTML, Rational Clear Case, Rational Clear Quest, PERL, z/OS, OS/390 and MVS. I have extensively worked with different tools like ECLIPSE, SQL Navigator, ROSCOE, SPUFI, QMF, SCM, File-Aid, File Management and Endevor. Good exposure to developing IMS COBOL applications using RDz, z/Linux and comfortable with developing legacy modernization tool that help in migration and modernization.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Tesco Hindustan Service Center - May 2011 to March 2013

Analyzed the requirement analysis, designed specs and developed coding for club card, sales forecasting modules using COBOL, JCL, DB2, TSO, Endevor, SQL, Telon Online/Batch, REXX, Flat files, IMS DB, Crest Tool, SPUFI, File-Aid, File Management, SAR, CA7

- Created code, unit test case document and implemented new programs and subprograms as well as enhancements, modifications, and corrections to existing modules.
- Assisted Testing team to identify border case scenarios and identified data Sets for System Testing.
- Identified opportunities for further enhancements and refinements to standards, processes and systems.

Software Engineer

HCL Technologies - October 2009 to April 2011

Jan 2010- Nov 2010

- Created high level platform design documents, code, unit/functional test, document and implemented new programs using Assembler, COBOL, JCL, DB2, Roscoe, VSAM.
- Interacted with Client SME to accomplish the project requirements.
- Participated in Test design, plan review sessions with peers and other stakeholders
- Executed test cases, analyzed and reported test results to product teams

Software Mainframe Trainee

Macrosoft India Private Limited - July 2009 to September 2009

Performed coding, unit testing for client, RR Donnelley using MF COBOL, JCL, Flat Files, Shell Script, Perl, Unix and fixed the existing issues.

· Performed testing for peer modules.

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

Texas State University - San Marcos, TX January 2015 to May 2017

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Kerala June 2004 to January 2009

SKILLS

COBOL (5 years), DB2 (5 years), DATABASE (7 years), SQL (7 years), IMS (3 years), VSAM (3 years), FILE (5 years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/blessy-yohannan-12946a52

AWARDS

Graduate Excellence Award

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:- COBOL, PLI, REXX, C, C++, JAVA, PHP, Perl

Databases: - DB2, IMS DB, VSAM, MS ACCESS

Front End: - HTML /CSS, XML

Tools: - Microsoft SQL Server [...] MySQL, Oracle 10g, ECLIPSE, SQL Navigator, ROSCOE, VSAM

TSO/ISPF, SPUFI, QMF, TELON BATCH AND ONLINE, CREST, FILE AID

OLTP: - CICS, IMS DC

Operating Systems: - Windows, Unix, Linux, MVS, S/390, z/OS

GRADUATE PROJECTS - MS CS, TX STATE

Land Mark Super Center Online Auto Shopping Portal (Independent)

- Designed database using ER model using Normalization Techniques
- Unit Tested the Queries using MySQL and Sequence Pro Tool

Greater Retailers of Round Rock Platform and Web store (Team of 4)

- Designed and developed a store website and integrated with platform website.
- Used JAVA, MYSQL, HTML

Internet Search-Web Application (Team of 2)

- Designed and developed an electronic search engine website similar to Google.
- Used PHP, MYSQL and HTML